Back together for the first time, again.
A Mighty Wind is a comedy, music film directed by Christopher Guest.
Three eclectic, never-quite-famous folk bands come together for the first time in decades following the
death of their manager to put on an reunion concert in his honor, at the request of his son.
Jonathan Steinbloom, played by Bob Balaban.
Alan Barrows, played by Christopher Guest.
Terry Bohner, played by John Michael Higgins.
Mitch Cohen, played by Eugene Levy.
Laurie Bohner, played by Jane Lynch.
Jerry Palter, played by Michael McKean.
A Mighty Wind is a 2003 American mockumentary comedy film about a folk music reunion concert in which
three folk bands reunite for a television performance for the first time in decades.
Co-written (with Eugene Levy), directed, and composed by Christopher Guest, the film is widely acknowledged to reference folk music producer Harold Leventhal as the
inspiration for the character of Irving Steinbloom and more broadly parodies the American folk music revival of the early 1960s and its personalities.
The film stars Guest and Levy alongside many of their frequent collaborators, including Bob Balaban, John Michael Higgins, Jane
Lynch, Michael McKean, Catherine O'Hara, Parker Posey, Ed Begley Jr., Jennifer Coolidge, Harry Shearer and Fred Willard.
The tone is lighthearted.